KRISTIN ZINSER

Senior Software Engineer, Frontend: Los Angeles, CA (Remote-only)

kristinzinser@gmail.com : kristinzinser.com : www.linkedin.com/in/kristinzinser : github.com/kristinzinser

Skills + Software Overview:

- → JavaScript/jQuery, HTML, CSS
- ReactJS (mostly functional, some class)
- → GraphQL + REST
- → CSS-in-JS (Emotion, Glamour, Styled Components)
- → SASS/Less/CSS
- → MaterialUI/Bootstrap/Tailwind
- → React-testing-library / Jest

- → StorybookJS/reusable components and design systems
- → Browserstack
- → Photoshop/Zeplin/Sketch/Figma
- → GitHub workflow
- → Content management systems CMS → Responsive & Adaptive development (Zendesk/Wordpress/Built.io/Tumblr/ → VSCode/SublimeText/various IDEs BigCartel/etc)
- → Themes/Theming

- → Shortcut/JIRA/Trello
- → Accessibility concepts
- → Documentation
- → Cross-browser testing and functionality

More skills available on request

EXPERIENCE:

Senior Frontend Engineer: Chameleon.io - Los Angeles, CA (remote): January 2023 - Present

- → Works on customer dashboard building new UI/UX, using React and TailwindCSS
- → Creates, builds and maintains reusable React components while utilizing expertise in accessibility and design
- → Writes testable well documented code
- → Supports keeping the platform secure and reliable
- Mentor, support, and work closely with other frontend and backend engineers, including the CTO

Senior Frontend Engineer: The Noun Project - Los Angeles, CA (remote): February 2020 - January 2023

- → Lead efforts on creating and maintaining a reusable component library with standards for accessibility, using StorybookJS, while working closely with design + product on this project; created processes and standards for maintaining this reusable component library and design system
- → Wrote functional React components with hooks using CSS-in-JS (styled components) and GraphQL for new pages, with unit tests using react-testing-library + Jest
- → Maintained & updated legacy code (Django templates w/ Sass + jQuery/vanilla JS + class-based React components using REST endpoints)
- → Collaborated with product, design, backend, and other frontend team members, while also mentoring junior developers
- → Created and updated feature and component documentation
- Implemented and guided team on accessibility standards in new work while being SME on a11y concepts
- Conducted QA for features, using Browserstack and other manual testing
- Participated in code reviews & design reviews

Senior Frontend Engineer: Aspiration - Los Angeles, CA (remote): June 2019 - February 2020

- → Worked collaboratively with product owners and designers to figure out efficient solutions for our users
- Constantly improved the accessibility of products in implementing a11y-friendly concepts to React components
- → Used GraphQL with JavaScript and React components
- → Ensured a smooth developer experience from onboarding to deployment
- → Coordinated and communicated seamlessly across other technical and product teams
- Contributed to code reviews and other team processes
- → Updated living styleguide (React with CSS-in-JS in Storybook)
- → Wrote unit tests for React components

UI Developer : Spokeo, Inc. - Pasadena, CA : July 2016 - June 2019

- → Collaborated with backend developers, product managers, designers, marketing, and team members
- → Built responsive, cross-browser compliant web pages using HTML5, CSS3 (Sass) and Emotion/Styled Components (React CSS-in-JS), Ruby on Rails platform, Haml, Yml, JavaScript + jQuery/CoffeeScript / React components, & JSON
- Maintained and updated living styleguide (React with CSS-in-JS)
- → Kept assets organized and optimized
- Lead development on Zendesk support interface theming as well as ongoing refactoring and support
- → Triaged visual and cross-browser/device defects
- → Wrote feature specs with RSpec for Rails and Jest for React

Senior Frontend Developer: Red Blue Media (now: Guff, Inc.) - Los Angeles, CA: November 2015 - May 2016

- → Rebuilt, developed, and maintained frontend with new designs for both new and existing products
- → Maintained & created processes and procedure documentation
- → Guided with best practices for frontend development, scalability, and ease of updates and additions in the future
- → Estimated & tracked progress with tasks to meet development deadlines
- → Guided & provided assistance to junior developers
- → Contributed to private GitHub repositories
- → Compile code using task runners (Grunt)
- → Utilize HTML frameworks to minimize development time (Bootstrap)
- → jQuery and JavaScript DOM manipulations

Senior Frontend Developer: Guthy-Renker - Santa Monica, CA: June 2015 - August 2015

- → Brief position utilizing their Demandware IDE based shopping platform, with A/B testing
- → Legacy-code environment with PHP/Rails and SASS
- → Foundation framework
- → CodeKit, Photoshop, SublimeText, Dreamweaver
- → Site load optimization / debugging
- → Demandware / Eclipse IDE > XML file compiling

Senior Frontend Engineer: YP, Inc. - Glendale, CA: October 2013 - May 2015

- → Created HTML for high-volume traffic websites, emails, landing pages and microsites
- → Problem-solved HTML/CSS layout and size constraint issues & created unique solutions
- → Provided new features and functionality for existing sites
- → Maintained consistency of site appearance via use of style guides, style sheets and enforcement of established standards and best practices
- → Translated Photoshop files with near pixel perfection
- → Provided all browser compatible HTML code to back end developers based on design
- → Collaborated with designers/back end developers to implement HTML/CSS code
- → Used SVN for version control, Bootstrap framework for frontend development, and custom jQuery/JavaScript

Senior UI Developer + Designer : Lancope, Inc. (now: owned by Cisco) - Alpharetta, GA : October 2012 - October 2013

- → Split time 50/50 between design & frontend development
- → Worked closely with back-end developers to ensure the integrity of the design & frontend development was upheld in the process
- → Lead design efforts from initial design concept wireframes through development of HTML & CSS
- → Transformed highly complex concepts/data into simple, user friendly designs with a strong eye for usability, layout & information hierarchy
- → Occasionally assisted with wireframing (using Balsamig)
- → Guided in the design process while aiding with expertise in design standards
- → Created design mock ups based on wireframe requirements while analyzing requirements & ensuring they are translated visually and functionally to the UI design and overall usability of the products
- → Created interaction models, user task flows, screen designs, and UI details that promoted ease of use and optimized the user experience
- → Built out the frontend of the designs selected for use with HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, minor jQuery, minor JavaScript
- → Tested for functionality and usability for cross-browser compatibility in all major browsers

Senior Frontend Developer + Designer : Apogee, Inc. - Atlanta, GA : March 2010 - October 2012

- → Lead Interactive multi-channel projects from concept to completion, with hands-on design work on multiple projects such as digital campaigns and websites, as well as traditional print/graphic/production work
- → Managed multiple deadlines and consistently delivered creatives on target and in a timely manner. Presented creative solutions and worked in partnership with the Account Managers. Designed website layouts for energy-industry clients.
- → Mentored junior developers and helped to interview and hire junior developers
- → Worked on a wide range of projects to build prototype user interface layouts for usability testing, client review and sales demonstrations, as well as serving as a knowledge resource for the latest trends and technologies for web standards-based user interface development.
- → Designed and built websites using HTML and CSS layouts for implementation into CMS tools (Sitefinity [ASP.Net] and WordPress [PHP]), while utilizing JavaScript and jQuery, with a heavy focus on cross-browser compatibility and user experience.
- → Worked closely with back-end developers to implement and execute web development projects.

ABOUT ME:

I'm fueled by sparkling water, pictures of cats, and learning. I like coding because I enjoy the idea of creating something from nothing, and ever since I was a kid, solving problems. I am passionate about clean, DRY code, and am always open to feedback on how to improve. I have a background in project management and web/print design, and have even had a stint as an Art Director - this has all helped me learn so much about why collaboration is important for a product that everyone can be proud of. I have enjoyed the frontend side of development for over 13 years now, and my background in design helps with my ability to improve and anticipate certain design and UI requirements; I also know what requirements to ask of a Product Manager or a Scrum master regarding expectations. You will usually find me squinting at my screen moving some pixels around, or hanging out in Pasadena with my husband and small cat. My current interests are in researching ways to bring accessibility into the work I do across the web to continue to try to be all-inclusive in my work. I also have a passion for creating and maintaining reusable component libraries with design system tokens, as I really love the user interface design aspect of things given my prior experience as a designer.

EDUCATION:

- JavaScript Part-Time Immersive, General Assembly Los Angeles, 2017 2018
- Associates in Arts Interactive Media Design (Design + Development), Art Institute of Atlanta, 2002 2004

For further work experience prior to 2010 + references, please contact kristinzinser@gmail.com